Never stab the devil in the back!
John Wick: Chapter 2 is a action, thriller, crime
film directed by Chad Stahelski.
John Wick is forced out of retirement by a former associate looking to
seize control of a shadowy international assassins’ guild.
Bound by a blood oath to aid him, Wick travels to Rome and does battle
against some of the world’s most dangerous killers.
John Wick, played by Keanu Reeves.
Cassian, played by Common.
Bowery King, played by Laurence Fishburne.
Santino D'Antonio, played by Riccardo Scamarcio.
Ares, played by Ruby Rose.
Charon, played by Lance Reddick.
John Wick: Chapter 2 is a 2017 American neo-noir action thriller film
directed by Chad Stahelski and written by Derek Kolstad.
As the direct sequel to John Wick (2014), it is the second
installment in the John Wick film series.
The film stars Keanu Reeves as the title character, with a supporting cast of Common, Laurence Fishburne, Riccardo
Scamarcio, Ruby Rose, Lance Reddick, Peter Stormare, Bridget Moynahan, Franco Nero, John Leguizamo, and Ian McShane.
The film's plot follows retired hitman John Wick (Reeves) as he is forced back into his old
life to fulfill a blood oath to crime lord Santino D'Antonio (Scamarcio).
Following the box office success of the previous film, Stahelski and the first film's uncredited
co-director David Leitch said a sequel film began development in February 2015.
Later that same month, Jon Feltheimer confirmed plans for additional John Wick properties to create a
media franchise, and announced the return of Kolstad as the sequel's screenwriter.
Principal photography began in October 2015 and lasted until early that following year,
with filming taking place in Montreal, New Jersey, New York City, and Rome.
John Wick: Chapter 2 had its premiere at the Arclight Hollywood in Los Angeles on January
30, 2017, and was released by Lionsgate in the United States on February 10.
The film received acclaim from critics, with praise for the action sequences, direction,
editing, visual style, and the performances of the cast, particularly Reeves.
It grossed US$174.3 million worldwide, becoming the
then-highest grossing film in the franchise.
A sequel, John Wick: Chapter 3 – Parabellum, was released in May 2019.
The film explores themes of martial arts, assassin, hitman, italy, roof.
The tone is dark and intense.